[{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Hardly had the journey started,\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..the car engine developed a fault.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["That","When","Than","soon"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>The story she was reading made her \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Laughed","To laugh","Laugh","Laughing"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<\/b><br><\/p><p><b>I am not going to the stadium with you as I ________ that team play before<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Am seeing","Have seen","Had seen","Was seeing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>The visitor was very uncomfortable because of his ______ nose<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Runny","Watery","Flowing","Running"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>&nbsp;_______you should put in some effort to show that you are interested.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["However you are tired","However tired you are","However tired are you","However is you tired"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase underlined<\/b><br><\/p><p><b>My brother\r\nmarried a <u><i>loquacious<\/i><\/u> woman<\/b><\/p>","options":["quiet","noisy","talkative","beautiful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>This engine is _____ that one.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Superior","More superior than","more superior to","superior to"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>I could not attend the meeting, so I asked my sister to stand _____ for me<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["up","by","in","on"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Since we were given all the things we requested, we should _______ with what we have<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Make up","Make on","make do","make with"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Must you always _____ lies? Why don\u2019t you ______ the truth for once?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["speak","say","talk","tell"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Don\u2019t let him bully you, you must stand up ______&nbsp; him<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["for","before","to","against"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>In this letter there ______ good news about your elder brother<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["is some","are","to","against"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Here\u2019s the book you wante(d) Is there anything ______ I can get you?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["more","against","else","other"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>My father _______ to smoke a lot, but he gave it up several years ago<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["was used","has been","is used","used"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>This classic ______ with enjoyment for nearly two hundred years.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["has been read","will have been read","shall have been read","was read"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>The old railway station has been turned ______ a very smart restaurant.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["in","into","on","onto"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Let\u2019s try to get home quickly before the rain really ______<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["sets in","sets on","sets off","sets down"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Are you able to ______ CDs on your computer<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["toast","cook","bake","burn"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>In study hall, I ______ Paul Smith, who is captain of the swim team and one of the best swimmers\r\nin the state.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["sit besides","sat beside","have set beside","sit beside"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Many 19th\r\n-century biographers _________ not on real facts.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["rely on their imagination","relied on their imagination","have relied on their imagination","could have relied on their imagination."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Knock _________ you enter the head of the department\u2019s office.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["As","When","Before","As\/when"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>The patient is suffering from ________&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["reumatism","rheumatism","Rhiumantism","reumantism"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>When he asked her to marry him, Ada was _____ than she had thought possible<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["happier","more happier","so happy","too happy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>He\u2019s a cockney: he was born and _______ up in London.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["bread","bred","brought","brought"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>If Kennedy _______ been killed, he would have been president for four years.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["have not","has not","hasn\u2019t","hadn\u2019t"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>When his wife died, he was _______ with grief.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["has been overcome","been overcame","overcome","overcame"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letter(s)\r\nunderlined.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>L<u>u<\/u>ck<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["lack","tum","lock","brother"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letter(s)\r\nunderlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>G<u>ua<\/u>rd<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Guide","Argue","Chat","Gourd"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/span><\/p><p><b>B<u>ee<\/u>r<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Fair","Bear","Pier","Pear"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/span><\/p><p><b>N<u>i<\/u>ne<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Pint","Gill","Pin","Click"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>B<u style=\"\">ea<\/u>r<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Beer","Steer","Rare","Fear"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>He could not have rewarded them more handsomely.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["He did not reward them very well","He rewarded them well and he was also a good looking man","He rewarded them very well","He spoke to them in a very generous way"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder; font-size: 0.875rem;\">Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/span><\/p><p><b>My advice to Tolu was \u2018look before you leap\u2019<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Tolu was advised to consider her options before reaching any decisions.","Tolu was advised to consider possible consequences before taking action.","Tolu was advised to weigh her decisions by looking and leaping.","Tolu was advised to leap only after looking."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/span><\/p><p><b>The official had allegedly been taking bribes<\/b>.<br><\/p>","options":["Some people accused the official of taking bribes","The official had been taking bribes without feeling any guilt.","It was proved that the official had been taking bribes","The official accused some people of taking bribes."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.&nbsp;<\/b><\/p><p><b>Emeka hardly ever holds with my view on good governance.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Emeka sometimes opposes my idea of good governance","My view of what good governance is conforms with that of Emeka","Emeka never really supports my opinion of good governance.","Emeka may never hold a view which conflicts with mine on good governance."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>There\u2019s a door at either end of the building<\/b>.<br><\/p>","options":["The building has two ends and two doors","The building has two ends but only one door","The building has two ends but i do not know which of the two has a door","The building has many ends, each with a door"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the options the word that has the same consonant sounds as the underlined\r\nletter(s) in each word.<\/b><\/p><p><b><u>Th<\/u>ough<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["theater","taught","weather","fate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the options the word that has the same consonant sounds as the underlined\r\nletter(s) in each word.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Cali<u>ph<\/u><\/b><br><\/p>","options":["presently","perhaps","powerful","opponent"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose from the options the word that has the same consonant sounds as the underlined letter(s) in each word.<\/span><\/p><p><b>Pas<u>t<\/u><\/b><br><\/p>","options":["Wrestle","Faith","Castle","Pasture"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word(s) or phrases underlined.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Uche could not travel last December because of the <u>severity<\/u> of the harmattan.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["cold","mildness","warmth","moderation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word(s) or phrases underlined.<\/b><br><\/p><p><b>Mrs. Koffi is very <u>provocative<\/u> in her style of dressing.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["inspiritional","repressive","disturbing","outrageous"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word(s) or phrases underlined.<br><\/b><\/p><p><b>Travelling in the night can be <u>an ordeal<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["A great experience","a great fear","a great endurance","a great pleasure"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word(s) or phrases underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Akoso thought that her father was <u><i>callous<\/i><\/u>.<\/b><\/p>","options":["indifference","compassionate","wicked","careless"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the words or phrase in italics.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Ugo has often been described as <u><i>belligerent<\/i><\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["attractive","patient","innocent","combative"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the words or phrase in italics.<\/b><\/p><p><b>While the thugs exchange blows, we looked <u><i>complacently<\/i><\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["dejectedly","sorrowful","questioningly","contentedly"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the words or phrase in italics.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Tade became <i><u>timorous<\/u><\/i> when she was asked to give the valedictory speech.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["excited","nervous","aggressive","happy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the words or phrase in italics.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The players kept on <i><u>gamely<\/u><\/i> to the end of the match.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["amateurishly","skillful","courageously","stubbornly"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the words or phrase in italics.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Art lies in cherishing the initiative and <u><i>creative power<\/i><\/u> of each person.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["potential","strength","gift","mind"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the appropriate <i>stress pattern<\/i> from the option. The syllables are written capitals.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Jurisprudence<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["JUrisprudence","juRISprudence","jurisPRUdence","jurispruDENCE"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the appropriate <i>stress pattern<\/i> from the option. The syllables are written capitals.&nbsp;<\/b><\/p><p><b>Suburbanite<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["SUburbanite","suBURbanite","suburBAnite","suburbaNITE"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the appropriate <i>stress pattern<\/i> from the option. The syllables are written capitals.&nbsp;<\/b><\/p><p><b>Departmentalize<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["departMENtalize","dePARTmentalize","Departmentalize","departmenTAlize"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the appropriate&nbsp;<i>stress pattern<\/i>&nbsp;from the option. The syllables are written capitals.&nbsp;<\/span><\/p><p><b>Organise<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["ORganise","orGAnise","orgaNISE","orGANISE"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The state government appointed a commission of inquiry <u>to go into<\/u> the community\u2019s complaints carefully and\r\nwithout prejudice.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["investigate","search","look for","account for"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The traffic situation in Lagos can lead to disastrous consequences; a man lost a very lucrative job because he\r\nwas <u>held up<\/u>&nbsp;by it.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["confused","delayed","annoyed","intrigued"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The two sprinters were running <u>neck and neck<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["exactly level","very slowly","very fast","together"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>He <u>stared<\/u> at her.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["glanced","peeped","looked","gazed"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>When the man was caught by the police, he <u>presented a bold front<\/u>.&nbsp;<\/b><\/p>","options":["he attacked the policeman","he walked up to the policeman","he faced the situation with apparent boldness","he bravely attempted to give them a present"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>I have been able to observe him <u>at close quarters<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["in government house nearby","within a short space of time","in a small family house","at close range"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that most suitably fills the space.<\/b><\/p><p><b>When the beggar was tired he ______&nbsp; down by the roadside.<\/b><\/p>","options":["lied","laid","layed","lay"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<i>most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>He did not like ______ leaving the class early.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["we","us","our","ourselves"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;most suitably&nbsp;fills the space.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The boy was born before his parents actually got married and so the court has cleared him ________<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["illegal","illegitimate","illicit","unlawful"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>As he was still owing me two Naira, I was careful not to _____&nbsp; him any more money.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["lend","loan","borrow","credit"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>If you travel by air you will be given an allowance to cover _______<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["a luggage","luggage","luggages","a baggage"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">&nbsp;Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<i>most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>He went up quickly and returned _______<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["fastest","fastly","as fastly","as fast"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\"><b>Invariably,\r\nhe ends his letters with ______ amicably.<\/b><\/span><\/p>","options":["yours'","your\u2019s","yours","your own"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>Our plane was scheduled to _______ at 10:00 hrs but it was delayed because of the bad weather.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["fly out","take off","start out","shoot off"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>If I went to the cinema, I _____ early<\/b>.<br><\/p>","options":["shall return","am returning","would return","may return"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that <i>most suitably<\/i> fills the space.<\/b>\r\n<br class=\"Apple-interchange-newline\"><\/p><p><b>Before we left the train station, each passenger was made to ______ certain form.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["fill in","write in","enter in","go through"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<i>most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span>&nbsp;<\/p><p><b>The managing director did not pay his staff last month, ________?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["didn\u2019t he","had he not","is not it","did he"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<i>most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>The train rattled along ____ full speed.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["in","at","with","on"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>If this had happened to you, what ______?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["would you do","have you done","would you have done","will you do"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>There were so many children ________ .<\/b><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\"><br><\/span><br><\/p>","options":["that she couldn\u2019t feed them all","that she could feed","that she couldn\u2019t feed","that she could feed them all"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>In West Africa, the _______ of sickle cell is about 25 percent.<\/b><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\"><br><\/span><br><\/p>","options":["incident","incidence","accident","accidence"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Complete the following sentence by choosing the option that&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-weight: 700;\">most suitably<\/i><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">&nbsp;fills the space.<\/span><\/p><p><b>We got to the hall after the play ______<\/b><b style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;<\/b><\/p>","options":["is started","was starting","had started","has started"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>For all he cared, his parent might have been dead for years.<\/b><\/p>","options":["although concern about his parent, he had been unable to find out if they were alive","he cared for no one except his parents, and it was possible that they had died long before","he did not care whether his parents were alive or had died","he was concerned about everyone not just his parents who might have died long before"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Had she asked me earlier, I might have been able to employ him.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["I employed her","I did not employ him","I employed him","I did not employ her"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>As he was a gullible leader, his followers took advantage of him.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["He was weak and unable to enforce his authority","He was simple-minded to a fault.","He was partial and unfair in dispensing justice.","He was slow to act"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).<\/b><\/p><p><b>I didn\u2019t think she could be so easily <u>taken in<\/u> by his pretences.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["flattered","deceived","overcomed","blackmailed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the\r\noption nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).<\/b><\/p><p><b>The story told by the suspect was <u>difficult to believe<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["incredulous","credible","credulous","ridiculous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option\r\nnearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).<\/b><\/p><p><b>Most of his observations were <u>wide of the mark<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["comprehensive","irrelevant","pertinent","came rather late"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).<\/b><\/p><p><b>He heard a <u>loud noise<\/u> of the huge air-raid siren.<\/b>&nbsp;<br><\/p>","options":["buzz","crack","rumble","whistle"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option that completes the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The young teacher was surprised that his promotion was approved by the old inspector who is generally known\r\nto_______<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["be generous","be friendly to young people","be hard to please","be very careful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b> Complete the following with the appropriate answer to the question.<\/b><\/p><p><b>John, would you mind lifting this box? <\/b><br><\/p>","options":["yes, I mind","no, I don\u2019t","no, I do","yes, I don\u2019t mind"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the\r\nexpression or word which best completes the sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>It was a long poem but he learnt it ______<\/b><\/p>","options":["off head","in memory","by heart","at heart"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Only the <u>small fry<\/u> get punished for such social misdemeanors&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["small boys","unimportant people","frightened people","frivolous people"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>He spoke with <u>his heart in his mouth<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["nervously","with such unusual cowardice","with a lot of confusion in his speech","with fright and agitation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>His jail terms were run <u>concurrently<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["simultenously","uniformly","laboriously","judiciously"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The bill has to wait as we are now <u>insolvent<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["overworked","bankrupt","unsettled","affluent"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>All his plans <u>fell through<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["failed","were accomplished","had to be reviewed","were rejected"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>The result of his experiment represents a <u>breakthrough<\/u> in medical science.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["an outstanding success","catastrophe","breaking point","colossal failure"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>He was appointed specifically <u>to put the recruits through<\/u>.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["assign them to work","train them","discipline them","assist them at work"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best conveys the meaning of the underlined portion of the below sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Mrs Dada has been deserted by her husband because he feels she has a <u>heart of stone<\/u>.&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["she has a heavy heart","she has little warmth of feeling","she has a cruel nature","she is hard-hearted"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the option that <i>most suitably<\/i> fills the gap in the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Before the operation, the dentist found that his patient\u2019s teeth \u2026 .&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["have long decayed","have been decayed","have long been decayed","had long decayed"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b> Choose the option that <i>most suitably<\/i> fills the gap in the sentence below. <\/b><\/p><p><b>In order to carry out the necessary examination, the dead body was...&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["extracted","extradited","exiled","exhumed"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that&nbsp;<i>most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the gap in the sentence below.<\/span><\/p><p><b>He went abroad with a view ____ a business partner.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["to find","to be finding","to have found","to finding"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that&nbsp;<i style=\"\">most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the gap in the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>He had just entered the office _____ the telephone rang.<br><\/b><br><\/p>","options":["as","before","since","when"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that&nbsp;<i style=\"\">most suitably<\/i>&nbsp;fills the gap in the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>My father cannot bear the _______ of the concoction that emanates from my mother\u2019s soup pot.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["scent","aroma","smell","savour"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the word or phrase nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>In some parts of our society, people are <u>ostracized<\/u> purely on the basis of their parentage.&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["included","disrespected","befriend","rejected"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the word or phrase nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Sitting majestically on his throne is the Oba of Benin <u>flanked<\/u> by his wives.&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["surrounded","supported","guarded","protected"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the appropriate option to fill the gap in the sentence below.<\/b><\/p><p><b>As a result of the injury sustained on the football field, Sola was \u2026 with a broken leg for months.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["laid off","laid out","laid on","laid up"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b> Choose the word or phrase nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>I listened with rapt attention as he never suspected that I knew he was telling me a <u>cock and bull story<\/u><\/b><br><\/p>","options":["a story about a cock","a story about a bull","made-up story","an interesting story"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the word or phrase nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>When a man is<u> immune<\/u> to an illness, he is&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["opposed to it","attached to it","hated by it","protected against it"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the best option to fill the gaps in the following sentence.<\/b><br><\/p><p><b>\r\nShall we go to the union meeting? No thank you, I do not feel like \u2026 anywhere.&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["go","going","to go","to have gone"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the best option to fill the gaps in the following sentence.<\/b><br><\/p><p><b>I started writing this test at 8:00am. It is 10:00am now. By 11:00am, I \u2026 it for three hours.&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["shall be writing","have been writing","shall have been writing","was writing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the best option to fill the gaps in the following sentence.<\/b><br><\/p><p><b>Don\u2019t study on the examination day. What did he tell you? He told me \u2026 on the examination day. <\/b><br><\/p>","options":["no studying","don\u2019t study","not study","not to study"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the\r\nbest option to fill the gaps in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>I am a student and \u2026 Musa. I left for the university, and \u2026 Musa.&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["was, does","so is, so did","so was, so does","he is, he did"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>&nbsp;Choose the\r\nbest option to fill the gaps in the following sentence.<\/b><\/p><p><b>You have been absent from classes for four months. How can you \u2026 for the lost time?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["make in","make up","make off","make out"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A realistic novel is one in which the characters are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Real","Historic","Just of above average intelligence","The types that we meet in everyday life"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"}]